Yesterday at OpenAI dev day, Sam Waltman
walked on the stage in San Francisco and
said, "Your entire tech stack is
deprecated." That's not a direct quote.
I'm just paraphrasing. But we have about
a half dozen newly released features
that will change the way developers
build AI powered apps in the future. The
biggest bet OpenAI is making is turning
Chat GPT into an app platform, which
means you no longer have to use
old-fashioned websites or mobile apps
like a boomer. The goal is to make chat
GPT like an operating system that you're
completely locked into. Imagine this.
You want to play your favorite song on
Spotify, like I'm quitting Prozac to
continue drinking by 19-year-old pop
sensation Jimmy Brown. In the future,
you no longer need to open the Spotify
app and hit the play button. Instead,
you can simply open the Chat GPT app and
type out an awkward prompt to tell Chat
GPT to push the button for you. Looks
like the future of AI is going to skip
the Great Robot War of 2029 prophesized
in Terminator and go straight to the
year of 255 prophesized in Idiocracy.
Well, there plenty of tards out there
living really kick-ass lives.
But developers who ride the chat GPT
apps wave early stand to make tons of
money from the massive distribution
opportunity of their 800 million weekly
active users. But apps and chat GPT
isn't the most interesting announcement.
You also need to know about agent kit
codecs with GitHub actions, new models
for poor people, and some big updates to
the API. It is October 7th, 2025, and
you're watching the code report. First,
let's talk more about apps and chat GPT.
remember GPT plugins from a couple years
ago? They died. Then they tried a slight
variation GPTs, but they're also pretty
much dead. And now they're trying apps
and chat GPT because the third time's a
charm. Right. Right now it's only being
triled by big apps you probably
recognize. And I think it could work
really well for things like Zillow. Like
this guy paid his realtor $50,000 for
this million-doll home in San Francisco.
When in reality, Chat GPT could have
done a better job faster. However, I'm
also pretty bearish on apps and chat GPT
because in most cases, I'd rather just
use an app's UI than rope in a chatbot
to over complicate things. The next
thing you should know about are updates
to the OpenAI API. Both Sora 2 and GPT5
Pro are now available in the API, which
means you can start lighting money on
fire trying to build your own AI powered
and shitification accelerator. The Sora
2 costs 50 cents per 1 second of
highquality video or about $1,800 to
slop out a 1-hour movie that nobody's
going to watch. In addition, if you're
implementing voice or image generation
features, there's now two smaller models
that are far less expensive than the
alternatives, but pretty cool. But one
of the greatest life hacks for
developers is to stop wasting time on
code reviews. OpenAI just released a
GitHub action for codecs that will
automatically review code quality every
time you make a new PR on GitHub. And
not just that, but you could also use it
to scan for security flaws, write
documentation, and a bunch of other
stuff. The coolest thing announced
yesterday though is agent kit, a unified
set of tools where developers can build,
deploy, and optimize agents. Just a few
days ago, I was talking about how
awesome N8N was as a Zapier alternative,
while now Agent Kit drops as the NAN
alternative for building AI apps. It
gives you a flowchart style canvas where
you can implement the logic for your app
without stitching together a bunch of
code manually. On one hand, this tool
has a lot of potential because it gives
non-engineers the ability to build
non-trivial apps. But on the other hand,
no code tools like this always have a
complexity ceiling that eventually
requires a real human programmer to come
in and tear the entire thing down and
build it properly with actual code. In
any case, it's a legit new tool that you
should have on your radar. Speaking of
which, you also need to know what Jet
Brains is up to, the sponsor of today's
video. They just launched a new AI
coding agent called Juny that's tightly
integrated with the Jet Brains IDE and
can understand the context of your
entire codebase. This allows it to fit
seamlessly into your workflow is so you
can have it complete realworld jobs at
your job without the need to context
switch between multiple tools. I've been
using Juni on my own side project that
has a bunch of complex geospatial data.
And my honest opinion is that it's a
little bit slower than other codegen
tools I've tried, but it handles context
and accuracy extremely well on a big
project. That's huge if you're on a big
team and it integrates well with
external platforms like GitHub where you
can assign multiple jobs to Juny at the
same time and have it complete all of
them asynchronously. Use the link below
to try out Juny for yourself today. This
has been the code report. Thanks for
watching and I will see you in the next
one.